

Dennis Madsen, Ph.D. github in linkedin personal **youtube**



SUMMARY

I am a dedicated Machine Learning Engineer who can take projects from raw data to full operation and continuous monitoring. I have a Ph.D. and an M.Sc. in Computer Science and Mathematics, specializing in computer vision and computer graphics, and a B.Sc. in Electrical Engineering.

My focus is on real-world machine-learning applications that add value. I am keen on classical computer vision and machine learning methods, probabilistic methods, and generative models.

I am a continuous learner who likes new challenges and acquiring new skills, e.g., through lecturing, pitch competitions, coding hackathons, and video creation.

SKILLS _

Artificial Intelligence (AI) | Machine Learning (ML) | Computer Vision (CV) | Statistical Shape Models Generative Models | Entrepreneurship | Prototyping | Research & Development | Medical Computer Vision | Probability and Statistics | Software Engineering | Video Editing | Public Speaking | Lecturing

Linux

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Experienced: Python | Scala | Javascript Knowledgeable: C | Bash | Java | VHDL | SQL

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES PyTorch | PyTorch Lightning | Jupyter | Matplotplib | Numpy | Pandas | Scikit-learn | Monai | VTK

| ITK | Nibabel | Scipy | Pytest | Tensorflow | Threejs | React | Scalismo **SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT**

Programming Paradigms | GIT | CLI | Docker | DVC | Debugging | Agile Methodology | MlOps Life-

cycles | CI/CD | Open-source

LANGUAGES Native: Danish Fluent: English Advanced: German

EXPERIENCE

University of Zürich (Zürich, Switzerland)

03.2023 - 04.2024

Postdoctoral Researcher - Bridge Proof-of-Concept fellow.

• Computer vision research on CBCT and IOS images for dental applications.

Dentexion GmbH (Zug, Switzerland)

01.2022 - 05.2024

Founder - Building an AI powered cloud-platform for dentists.

- Developing a fully automatic SaaS platform to upload and analyze dental images (cloud-based) for preventive care.
- On the technical side I was responsible for all ML aspects and computer graphics (Threejs).

University of Basel (Basel, Switzerland)

08.2021 - 02.2023

Postdoctoral Researcher

University of Basel (Basel, Switzerland)

09.2017 - 07.2021

Research Assistant / Ph.D. Candidate / Lecturer

- Research in the area of medical computer vision using statistical shape models.
- · Lecturing the Pattern Recognition course for bachelor students on probability theory and deep learning.

Capana (Denmark, remote from Switzerland) Consultant

07.2016 - 12.2019

• Developing internal productivity tools for Seimens Wind Power in Python and Web2Py.

• Full application lifecycle, from identifying needs, planning to development and production.

Siemens Wind Power (Brande, Denmark) **Embedded Software Support Engineer**

04.2014 - 08.2015

• Work task automation of manual procedures; software updates and support of Siemens Wind Turbine Controllers.

Litepoint (Sunnyvale, California, USA) **Electronic Engineer Intern**

04.2013 - 09.2013

• Creating a test system interface to check cell-phone cellular data signal using a local Django application.

Dennis Madsen, Ph.D. Page 1 of 3

Microdevelopment (Herning, Denmark)

11.2009 - 09.2014

Founder - Producing electronic speed tables for use in historical reliability races.

· Software development in C for a PIC microcontroller, web development with payment system and customer contact.

KK-Electronic (Ikast, Denmark)

01 2006 - 03 2014

Electronic Industrial Technician Trainee / Embedded Software Engineer Student

• HW design, embedded SW (C/assembler), documentation, prototyping (mechanic, PCB, test scripting), HW coding (VHDL).

EDUCATION

University of Basel (Basel, Switzerland)

2017 - 2021

Ph.D. Computer Science & Mathematics (Summa cum laude)

- Thesis: A Probabilistic Surface Registration Framework with Applications to Partial Data Analysis.
- · Model-based medical image analysis focused on registration and modelling using partial data and reconstruction uncertainty.

University of Basel (Basel, Switzerland)

2015 - 2017

M.Sc. Computer Science & Mathematics (6.0 / A)

• Thesis: Craniofacial modelling by combining statistical models of the face and the skull - Combining independent shape models.

Aarhus University (Herning, Denmark)

2010 - 2014

B.Sc. Electronic Design Engineer (12.0 / A)

• Thesis: Power quality analysis of wind turbines - Harmonic frequency analysis prototype implementation in a TI DSP.

Aarhus University (Herning, Denmark)

2009 - 2010

University pre-admission course
Mercantec (Viborg, Denmark)

2005 - 2009

Electronic Industrial Technician

CERTIFICATIONS

- Innosuisse Business Creation MEDTECH, Switzerland 2023
- Innosuisse Start-up Training: Business Concept (Module 2), Switzerland 2021
- Project Management A Toolbox for Scientists, Switzerland 2021

AWARDS & HACKATON PARTICIPATION

- Medical Imaging Summer School (Favignana, Italy) Best Presentation Award 2018
- EXCITE Summer school (Zürich, Switzerland) 2nd Best Presentation Award 2018
- CopenHacks (Copenhagen, Denmark) Price winner 2017
- LauzHack (Lausanne, Switzerland) Winner of the main sponsor (Logitech) challenge 2016
- HackZürich (Zürich, Switzerland) Europe's largest hackaton Participant 2016, 2017, 2018

OPEN-SOURCE SOFTWARE MAINTAINER

SCALISMO Scala library for statistical shape modeling

SCALISMO-UI Scala library for visualization of statistical shape models

GINGR Scala library for non-rigid registration (based on my PhD Thesis)

Dennis Madsen, Ph.D. Page 2 of 3

Books

A Probabilistic Surface Registration Framework with Applications to Partial Data Analysis

<u>Dennis Madsen</u> *University of Basel, 2021*

International peer-reviewed conferences/proceedings

Sequential gaussian process regression for simultaneous pathology detection and shape reconstruction

Dana Rahbani, Andreas Morel-Forster, <u>Dennis Madsen</u>, Jonathan Aellen, Thomas Vetter International Conference on Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2021

A closest point proposal for MCMC-based probabilistic surface registration

<u>Dennis Madsen</u>, Andreas Morel-Forster, Patrick Kahr, Dana Rahbani, Thomas Vetter, Marcel Lüthi *European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)*, 2020

Probabilistic joint face-skull modelling for facial reconstruction

<u>Dennis Madsen</u>, Marcel Lüthi, Andreas Schneider, Thomas Vetter *Proceedings of the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2018

International peer-reviewed workshops/proceedings

Learning Shape Priors from Pieces

<u>Dennis Madsen</u>, Jonathan Aellen, Andreas Morel-Forster, Thomas Vetter, Marcel Lüthi *International Workshop on Shape in Medical Imaging (ShapeMi)*, 2020

Probabilistic surface reconstruction with unknown correspondence

Dennis Madsen, Thomas Vetter, Marcel Lüthi

Uncertainty for Safe Utilization of Machine Learning in Medical Imaging and Clinical Image-Based Procedures (UNSURE), 2019

Robust registration of statistical shape models for unsupervised pathology annotation

Dana Rahbani, Andreas Morel-Forster, <u>Dennis Madsen</u>, Marcel Lüthi, Thomas Vetter Large-Scale Annotation of Biomedical Data and Expert Label Synthesis and Hardware Aware Learning for Medical Imaging and Computer Assisted Intervention (LABELS), 2019

Other

GiNGR: Generalized Iterative Non-Rigid Point Cloud and Surface Registration Using Gaussian Process Regression

<u>Dennis Madsen</u>, Jonathan Aellen, Andreas Morel-Forster, Thomas Vetter, Marcel Lüthi arXiv preprint arXiv:2203.09986 *(2022).* 2022

Dennis Madsen, Ph.D. Page 3 of 3